<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erasmian Programming Café</title>
    <link>/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erasmian Programming Café</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact us!</title>
      <link>/contact.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-are-here-to-help-you-improve-your-programming&#34;&gt;We are here to help you improve your programming&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you curious about something? Do you have some kind of problem with the Café?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contact us!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-who-is-it-for&#34;&gt;1. Who is it for?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Programming Café is for researchers (incl. PhDs) of all levels of programming, regardless of their field of study or level of experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beginner programmers can find a supportive environment that will connect you with like-minded, but also help you learn how to code and get the help you need&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced programmers can share their expertise and connect with other skilled programmers to stay up-to-date with the latest trends&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interdisciplinary researchers can find a supportive and collaborative environment here where they can learn programming skills that are relevant to their research&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data specialists can find a platform to connect with other researchers who share their interest, learn from each other and collaborate on data-driven research projects&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-why-should-i-invest-my-time&#34;&gt;2. Why should I invest my time?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Programming can be a daunting task, especially when you are just starting out, but it does not have to be a lonely one. If you help us building the community, we can support each other, learn from each other and grow together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Café on 18th November 2025</title>
      <link>/post/programming-caf-on-18th-november-2025.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/programming-caf-on-18th-november-2025.html</guid>
      <description>Our first Programming Café has been scheduled!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/resources.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking for other ways to improve your programming or just to learn something new?&#xA;We collected a list of resources that can help you on your journey.&#xA;The following content was and is continuously inspired by our Café colleagues from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ubvu.github.io/bytes-and-bites/learning_files/resources.html&#34;&gt;VU&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/open-science-roadmaps/awesome-research-software-training&#34;&gt;Awesome research software training list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;books-and-papers-on-programming&#34;&gt;Books and Papers on Programming&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://book.the-turing-way.org/reproducible-research/reproducible-research/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guide for Reproducible Coding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This guide gives insights into version control, licensing, and code documentation and can help you to improve the reproducibility of your research project!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005510&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper on good enough practices for scientific programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and (the fitting lesson on this topic from the Carepentries)[https://carpentries-lab.github.io/good-enough-practices/03-software.html] These resources can help you to better structure your project and good practices right from the start.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python-guide.org&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This handbook covers a wide range of Python-related topics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstats.wtf&#34;&gt;**What They Forgot to Teach You About R&amp;amp;*&lt;/a&gt; Interesting R content that goes beyond data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jaeyk.github.io/comp_thinking_social_science/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book about Computational Thinking for Social Scientists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This website is designed to help social science researchers to learn how to think computationally.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;workshops&#34;&gt;Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;within-eur&#34;&gt;Within EUR&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Carpentries for Social Sciences and Humanities&lt;/strong&gt; This course gives an introduction to R and nice tools such as OpenRefine. If you are an R beginner, attending this course is recommended. The next session will be in March 2026.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Python for Researchers&lt;/strong&gt; In January this course will give you an introduction to Programming Fundamentals using Python.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-level&#34;&gt;National level&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esciencecenter.nl/digital-skills/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netherlands eScience center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The eScience center regularly offers intermediate programming courses for researchers and support staff&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>/team.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/team.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;our-team&#34;&gt;Our team&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we are just starting the initiative, our team is rather small. However, we are looking for volunteers or staff members that want to help us with the Programming Cafés!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-team-members&#34;&gt;Our team members&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;helena-wedig-sheher&#34;&gt;Helena Wedig (she/her)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;./images/team/helena.jpeg&#34; style=&#34;float:left;width:15%;height:15%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; Helena Wedig works since June 2025 as Research Software and Interoperability Training Lead at ERS, where she leads efforts to enhance research software skills across the university. She is currently working on a NWO-funded project aimed at developing a comprehensive and integrated Research Software training program at EUR.&#xA;In this role, Helena is responsible for coordinating existing training offerings and designing new ones. &#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;b&gt;Background: &lt;/b&gt;After completing her studies in Computational Linguistics at Ruhr University Bochum in 2019, she worked as a Research Engineer at Fraunhofer IAIS in Germany. In 2021, she began her PhD in Linguistics at the University of Antwerp (Belgium), which she successfully completed in March 2025. In her PhD research, she compiled, processed, and annotated three language corpora and conducted statistical analyses to identify language-dependent features within them. Her programming languages of choice are R and Python.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
